<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://iancarras.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://iancarras.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-09T00:54:02-07:00</updated><id>http://iancarras.co/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ian Carrasco</title><subtitle>A blog, resume, and archive of things I'm interested in and have worked on.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Thoughts on Questions</title><link href="http://iancarras.co/blog/questions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Thoughts on Questions" /><published>2021-03-29T11:05:52-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T11:05:52-07:00</updated><id>http://iancarras.co/blog/questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://iancarras.co/blog/questions">&lt;p&gt;Questions are often seen (incorrectly) in many scenarios as illuminating one’s lack of understanding. I mean you are asking a question because you didn’t fully understand some information presented to you, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions are much more nuanced than they might seem in the form described above, a form which acts as a barrier for many people to ask questions in the first place. I view questions as one of the most powerful tools for understanding topics deeply, demonstrating knowledge, and having awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obsessive question asking keeps your mind on edge and rewards naivety. There are questions that may seem so base or fundamental at the surface many people overlook them and consequently having a harder time answering them. By asking these fundamental questions you put yourself in a postition to understand topics from the bottom up when certain aspects have already been placed in “common knowledge”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst children, there is a phase where they ask questions about the world in this obsessive way, as for them it is the only way to learn about why things are the way they are. As one gets older, however, question asking tends to slowly subside, due to much more consideration of how questions might be perceived by others. 
While it is an important consideration, don’t let it obstruct you’re own internal thought processes where these questions intially come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, be the person in the room that asks the questions nobody else will, in the minimum case it just further reaffirms understanding, in the best case it changes one’s understanding. So ask on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Perspective" /><summary type="html">Questions are often seen (incorrectly) in many scenarios as illuminating one’s lack of understanding. I mean you are asking a question because you didn’t fully understand some information presented to you, right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Notes from Talks/Books</title><link href="http://iancarras.co/blog/notes-talks-books" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes from Talks/Books" /><published>2020-09-25T11:05:52-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-25T11:05:52-07:00</updated><id>http://iancarras.co/blog/talks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://iancarras.co/blog/notes-talks-books">&lt;p&gt;This page is going to be an ongoing list of notes from talks/lectures/books I’ve watched and read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ajay-banga---taking-risks-in-your-life-and-career&quot;&gt;Ajay Banga - Taking Risks in Your Life and Career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going into a new company with a mindset of trying to learn from everyone.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everyone knows something that you don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Have humility, but be bold enough to take risks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have to enjoy what you are doing FIRST! If you aren’t, find it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the time for what matters (Health, Family, Relationships)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And make sure to spend that time with people not devices&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Important to consider what &lt;strong&gt;and how&lt;/strong&gt; you do something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deal with adversity, don’t try to avoid it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ashlee-vance---elon-musk-biography&quot;&gt;Ashlee Vance - Elon Musk Biography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;highly data-driven&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;rational&lt;/strong&gt; when making decisions and analyzing failures. This can be through extensively logging metrics, adding new sensors, etc… &lt;strong&gt;Prevent making the same mistake twice at all costs&lt;/strong&gt;.
This was heavily emphasized due to the large time and financial investment with SpaceX testing, but still should be generally applicable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Principles First Thinking - &lt;strong&gt;Don’t accept ideas on the basis of them being around for a long time&lt;/strong&gt;.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What made Tesla and SpaceX so innovative was the removal of a lot of the beureaucratic, slow development cycles that have plagued the automotive and aerospace industries. Think if an important component of a product can be redesigned to be faster, better, and cheaper, before accepting existing options. If the investment in optimizing this one part is too high that it could stunt overall progress, then evaluate other options.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen to well-structured arguments and don’t base resulting decisions on the merits of the people presenting them, but rather the argument in its logical form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loyalty and determination arises in the presence of adversity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to &lt;strong&gt;surround yourself with the best&lt;/strong&gt;. Know the places that the people you look up to frequent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set ambitious deadlines&lt;/strong&gt; in order to have work materialize faster. In the case that
a project runs longer than expected, there is still room to stay on schedule in the near-term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;john-ousterhout---a-philosophy-of-software-design-talk&quot;&gt;John Ousterhout - A Philosophy of Software Design Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build deeper classes as opposed to shallow classes. Don’t have interfaces whose cost of use is greater than the functionality it wraps (benefit). Treating classes in this cost benefit analysis approach can reduce complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create deep abstractions, don’t add layers where they are not needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The common use case for a given class should be easy, but still make edge cases possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimize places exceptions are caught.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Exceptions are most useful when they are thrown far.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design software for the future, going 10% slower today to make the right design choices, as they propagate in an engineering org.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tactical programmers just aim to have something work with minimal consideration of software design.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Having an engineering cultures that value software design principles attracts top talent.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire for slope not y-intercept.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Potential to learn quickly and grow (slope), is more valuable than the experience coming in (y-intercept), in most cases.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Perspective" /><summary type="html">This page is going to be an ongoing list of notes from talks/lectures/books I’ve watched and read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Technological Inertia</title><link href="http://iancarras.co/blog/inertia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technological Inertia" /><published>2019-12-22T10:05:52-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T10:05:52-08:00</updated><id>http://iancarras.co/blog/technological-inertia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://iancarras.co/blog/inertia">&lt;p&gt;With the start of the new decade I’ve been thinking
about what technologies might define it whether it be
(AR, AI, Edge Computing, 5G, etc.). When evaluating 
developments and trends in consumer tech and research, I found
myself continually thinking about the dynamics of how 
new technologies are adopted in society and make their way 
into the status quo. In particular, I came up with a 
concept I call &lt;em&gt;technological inertia&lt;/em&gt;, whose definition
might be trivial, but I felt succinctly captures an important 
consideration when ideating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;definition&quot;&gt;Definition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An idea has to be familiar enough that the learning/adoption curve is relatively
small such that it could be intially adopted by those who are comfortable with existing technological norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the idea has to add enough value or novelty to existing solutions, that one would give up using pre-existing 
technology in order to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers have inherent inertia, a tendency to stick with what works. When the balance of &lt;strong&gt;familiarity and innovation&lt;/strong&gt; of an idea is not level, this inertial force is greater than the “force”(marketing, innovation, design) of an idea. Thus, leading to minimal or low adoption. If this balance is maintained, an idea will have a much better chance at being adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The term is derived from inertia in classical mechanics, which is an object’s resistance to change or tendency to stay at rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Perspective" /><summary type="html">With the start of the new decade I’ve been thinking about what technologies might define it whether it be (AR, AI, Edge Computing, 5G, etc.). When evaluating developments and trends in consumer tech and research, I found myself continually thinking about the dynamics of how new technologies are adopted in society and make their way into the status quo. In particular, I came up with a concept I call technological inertia, whose definition might be trivial, but I felt succinctly captures an important consideration when ideating.</summary></entry></feed>